

Sathiyanarayanan Palani

Senior Engineer (Software / Automation Development)

About Me

Hello!

I'm Sathiyanarayanan Palani.

I am a senior Python Developer with adequate knowledge in C & C++.

I've worked as SDET & DevOps Engineer for development of embedded software Applications.

26 Age

Email sathiyanarayanan396@gmail.com

Phone +918072500974

Address 18/26 Rathna Nagar, Alpet,

Manjakuppam, Cuddalore,

Tamil Nadu, India

Professional Skills

Python	Proficiency in Communication
C/C++	Self-Learning/Problem-Solving
Jenkins/Docker	Proof-of-concept development

Skills

Category **Technologies**

Programming Languages:

C, C++, Python, Shell & Batch basics

Operating System:

Linux, windows

Communication

UART, I2C, SPI

Protocols:

Networking Protocols: TCP/IP, UDP, HTTP, MQTT, SQL

Source Code Management:

git Git, G Github

Tools and Libraries:

Gtest, FFF, Jenkins, Git, MySQL, OpenCV, Tkinter, paramiko, SCP, pandas, ASTREE, lark - parser, matplotlib, numpy,

pyYaml, rich, pytest

Web Technologies:

Node.js, react.js mui basics

DevOps:

Jenkins, Docker, kubernetes basics

PyPI:

🏓 LogExan, 🏓 ScEqAn, 🏓 py4cli (In Progress), 🏓 more

Work Experience (≈5 years)

Semiconductor S/W Product Development Engineer at UST Global, Bangalore

(May, 2022 - Present)

- · Responsible for Python Automation test framework, modification, maintenance & Improvement
- · Development of YAML based test runners for automatic report generation from return values of tester functions

Senior Engineer at lelektron Technologies, Chennai

(Oct, 2018 - Dec, 2021)

d

Software Validation Engineer at MBRDI, Bangalore (as External)

(Apr, 2019 - Dec, 2021)

- Responsible for writing test scripts for automated validation of measurements in python based on HIL scenarios from DOORS.
- · Responsible for HiL process Automation via SSH using python Libraries like paramiko and SCP.
- Responsible for development of Custom framework and reusable components in Python & Bash for automated test case generation using pandas data frames for pre-HIL execution task.
- Responsible for Runtime dynamic analysis of ADAS utility modules in c using ASTREE.
- · Responsible for unit testing, L2 testing using Google test framework in c++ based on Scenarios (SIL).

Python Developer at SAFRAN Aerospace, Bangalore (as External)

(Oct, 2018 - Mar, 2019)

- Responsible for Multi-Display Broadcast over local Network using TCP/IP.
- Responsible for Data Visualization of sensor plots in Aerospace Applications using python & plotly (3d scalar plots).
- Responsible for visualization of volumetric data in the form of normal distribution for the development of algorithm on event classification using Matplotlib.

Embedded Software Developer at lelektron Technologies, Chennai

(Jul, 2017 - Sep, 2018)

- Responsible for Embedded Software unit and functional Testing.
- Responsible for Embedded Software Development of iElektron Security Products.
- Development of multi-branch CI/CD pipeline in Jenkins for Unit Testing with github app integration for events and mail, slack integration for notifications.
- Responsible for development of semi-automated hardware testing platform for Renesas Microcontrollers using Iron-python Renesas APIs

Education

BE - Electrical and Electronics Engineering from Anand Institute of Higher Technology, chennai (affiliated to Anna University)

2013 - 2017

- Graduated with a first class in Electrical and Electronics Engineering.
- Final Year project done using OpenCV and Raspberry Pi for Automatic Attendance System using Face Recognition.

HSC from ARLM Matric Higher Secondary School, Cuddalore

2012 - 2013

• Completed with 85%

SSLC from SRV Matric Higher Secondary School, Trichy

2010 - 2011

• Completed with 85%